

A technical artist specialized in procedural tools creation with

8+ years' experience working on multiple big triple A games from Assassin greed to Farcry and assisting with development of procedural USD based pipelines from the Houdini's side. Practical problem solver and taking pride in making fast, stable and user-friendly tools.

Vertex_lighting

- Base Colo
- Metallic
- . . .
- Anisotropy
- C Emissive Col

Work experience:



Lightspeed studios

London 01/2024 – present Principle technical artist

- Using previous gained experience to advise on the development of a new in-house pipeline. Providing feedback on tools, interface, and general flow.
- Creating demo scenes for presentations
- River generator using the new USD based pipeline.



Ubisoft

Montreal, 09/2016 - 12/2023

Technical artist

- Work on different tools for these projects, ranging from simple to complex tools like:
 - o Fence placement tools.
 - o Railroad intersections combining custom meshes with premade models.
 - o Cliff scattering
 - o Rock collision and model generation.
- Creating the Import and Export nodes for the Houdini <-> Anvil pipeline.
- Improve performance on existing tools like Flow map generation making it 10x faster.
- Multiple prototypes and proofs of concepts.



Buas

Breda, 12/2015 - 06/2016 & 10/2014 - 12/2014 Teaching assistant

- Assisting student's with Houdini.
- Project related feedback to 3th year Art student's

Education:

Master of game technology

Buas (NHTV University of Applied Science) Breda, Netherlands 2014 – 2015

Bachelor in international game architecture & design

Buas (NHTV University of Applied Science) Breda, Netherlands 2010 – 2014

Activities and interests:

Sports: Gym, Martial arts, Bouldering, Others Hobbies: Games, Reading, Sports, Movies, Learning

Contact:

Email:

m.laanbroek@gmail.com

Portfolio:

https://mlaanbroekta.github.io/Portfolio/

LinkedIn:

linkedin.com/in/mauritslaanbroek

Games / Projects

- LightCraft pipeline
- Anvil Engine team
- AC Valhalla
- Far cry 5
- AC Odessey
- AC Origin

Skill:

Procedural tool dev

Houdini

Python

USD

UE Blueprints

UE PCG

UE Scriptable tools

PyQt, PySide

C#

UE Shaders

Performance optimization

Languages

Native

Netherlands English

Basic

French

German